One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
Ahh! It's gonna eat me!
ギャー！食われるー！
Eat this!
食らえ！
Outta the way, Iceburg!
どけ！どけ！アイスバーグ～！
Well...! What the hell are you doing, Franky?!
ンマー！ 何やってんだフランキー！
Idiot!
この！
Ow!
あっ
Well...!
ンマー！
What gives?! Why aren't you helping me work?!
お前は仕事も手伝わねえで何やってんだ
All you do is build this dangerous crap!
こんな危なっかしいもんばっかり造ってよ！
Shut up! It's none of your business, Dumburg!
うるせえな！お前には関係ないだろバカバーグ！
This is my favorite battleship, the Battle Franky!
これは俺の大事な戦艦 バトルフランキー号なんだ
I don't care! Just get rid of it before someone gets hurt!
何だか知らんが 誰かがケガする前に全部捨てろ！
I can keep whatever I want here! This is Scrap Island!
何置いても勝手だろ！ ここは廃船島なんだ！
Just you wait. My next battleship will thrash those sea kings!
見てろ　俺は次こそ 海王類に勝てる船艦を造ってやる！
Well, no chance! You'll be sea king food!
ンマー　勝てるか お前なんか食われちまえ！
I'll knock 'em down!
勝てるさ
Well, you won't!
ンマー！勝てねえ
Will too!
勝てる！
♪ A man gives his damn all! ♪
男なら～　ドンとやれ！
That wraps up the launch ceremony!
進水式終了だ
We sure built a damn, sturdy ship.
頑丈ないい船がドンとできた
Didn't we, Yokozuna?
なあ　ヨコヅナ
What do you say we finish it up tomorrow?
仕上げは明日にするか
Let's head home for now.
さあ　帰るぞ
Opposite the Warehouse Under the Bridge Water Seven
ああ腹減った
I wonder what's for dinner.
メシは何だろうな？
Hey...
ちょっと
– Wait, Mr. Tom! – Wait, Mr. Tom!
–　待ってよ　トムさーん！
So, what number is your Battle Franky at now?
バトルフランキーは今 何号だ？フランキー
Oh, it's at eight.
ん…　８号
It was so close this time!
惜しかったんだ～
Liar!
ウソつけ！
Man, your leniency just emboldens him, Mr. Tom!
まったく トムさんが許すから調子に乗るんだよ
All he makes are weapons!
こいつは武器ばっかり作ってよ
Shut up, Dumburg!
うっせえよ！バカバーグ！
What'd you say, Flunky?!
くっ…　何だと？このバカンキーが！
Flun... ky!
キッ…　なんだと！
Now, now... Stop fighting, you two.
はいはい ２人ともケンカはやめな
H-He called me "Flunky"!
バカ…
– But Miss Kokoro, he's the one who...!
–　だってココロさんこいつが！
Good grief...
まったく…
And that's enough laughing from you, Mr. Tom.
トムさんも笑いすぎだよ
What's gotten into you?
何がツボに入ったんだい？ああ
Oh, by the way,
そうそう　そういえば
I heard pirates raided another lumber hauler.
また木材を積んだ交易船が 海賊にやられたって
There've been more pirates than ever since the Pirate King's execution.
海賊王が死刑になった後 めっきり海賊が増えちまって
Our city's just about had it. The pirate age has engulfed us.
ダメだねもうこの町は… 海賊時代にのまれちまってる
It just feels hopeless.
気持ちで負けてんだね
The Aqua Laguna floods mean we need to rely on other islands to get us lumber and iron,
アクア･ラグナの浸水で 木材も鉄もよその島からしか手に入らなくなったところへ
but treacherous seas and pirates hamper trade.
凶暴な海や海賊たちが交易を阻む
The shortage of work means shipyards jockey for customers.
仕事の不足した造船所同士で客を取り合う
Fights break out and people lose their jobs.
ケンカが始まる　職は失う
Left unchecked, Water Seven, an island once renowned for its shipbuilding enterprise...
ほっときゃ　このウォーターセブンは 浸水を待つだけのほうけた島になっちまうよ
will become complacent with the status quo, just waiting for flood waters to overtake it.
昔は造船業で一時代を築いた このウォーターセブンがねえ
That's right! Mr. Tom once built that incredible pirate ship!
そうだよな トムさんもすげえ海賊船造ったんだもんな
Hey, show me blueprints for a pirate ship!
なあ！海賊船の設計図教えてくれよ！
Why are you laughing?!
何で笑うんだよ？
Franky, there's no such thing as blueprints for a pirate ship.
フランキー この世に海賊船の設計図なんてのはねえのよ
If sailors hoist a skull flag, that's a pirate ship.
乗り込んだ船乗りがドクロを掲げりゃ海賊船
Marine ships have a seagull flag.
カモメを掲げりゃあ海軍船だ
It doesn't matter what he wants to build,
何を造りたがろうと構わねえが
but a man should be damn proud of the ship he builds!
造った船に男はドンと胸を張れ！
Aren't you going to bed, Mr. Tom?
トムさん　寝ねえのか？
What're you drawing?
何描いてんだ？
Ah... This is the island's hope.
ああ　これはこの島の希望だ
Hope?
希望？
This idea might yet revitalize Water Seven.
これで　ウォーターセブンが 再生できるといいんだが…
Now, get some shut-eye.
さあ　もう寝な
Okay.
うん
Hm?
ん？
A government judicial ship is here!
政府の司法船が来たぞ！
What's a judicial ship?
何だ？司法船って
It's a mobile courthouse.
移動する裁判所だ
So who's on trial?
誰を裁きに来たんだ？
Wait a minute!
ちょっと待てよ
What did Mr. Tom do? Get the hell outta my way!
トムさんが何をしたんだよ！ 何だよ　どけよ！
Give Mr. Tom back, you jerks!
お前らトムさんを返せ！
It's okay. Don't worry.
大丈夫だ　心配するな
Mr. Tom! Mr. Tom!
トムさん！トムさーん！
Gold Roger, the King of the Pirates, was recently executed.
先日処刑された海賊王 ゴールド･ロジャーの海賊船
By building Gold Roger's ship, the Oro Jackson,
オーロ･ジャクソン号を製造した事実を
the shipwright Tom aided and abetted this criminal!
世界的凶悪犯への加担と見なし
For this world-class crime, Tom will be taken to Enies Lobby where he will be put to death!
造船技師トムをエニエス･ロビーへ連行 および死刑に処す！
What?!
えっ！？
Terrible news! Tom... Tom received a death sentence!
大変だー！トムが… トムが死刑になるぞー！
They say building the Pirate King's ship was a crime.
海賊王の船を造った罪だってよ
It's finally happened.
ついに来たか…
This caused problems for the whole world. He had it coming.
世界中迷惑してんだ しかたねえよ
Normally, it would not be a crime for a shipwright to sell their ship to anyone.
本来船大工が 誰に船を売ろうとも罪ではないが
However, the Pirate King warrants an exception.
海賊王に限っては特例だ
Anyone deemed to have anything to do with his piracy poses a danger to the world.
ヤツの海賊行為に少しでも肩入れしたと 見なされる者は全てが危険人物
Thus, I sentence you to death!
よって死刑
Take the convict away!
罪人を連行せよ
– Yes, Your Honor!
–　はっ
Let's go.
さあ行くぞ
Move it!
早く歩け
Come on...!
どうした？
Get moving!
早く行かないか
Hey, what are you doing?
おい！何をしている？
I'm currently designing...
わしは今…
Huh?
あっ
a paddle steamer that will bang along a railway on the ocean's surface.
海上の線路をドンと走る蒸気機関 パドルシップを構想している
Hey, you! Don't speak to him!
おい！貴様！何を言いだす
Get...
この…
As we speak, this island decays due to stagnant trade.
今や　廃れたこの島の その原因がままならねえ交易だとして
As we speak,
今や
the people are demoralized by their fear that the island will sink.
すさんだ人々の心が 沈む島を不安に思う気持ちだとして
Launching a sea train...
海列車の開通は
will definitely save our island, Water Seven!
いずれ必ずこのウォーターセブンの救いになる
E-Excuse us. We will remove him immediately.
し…　失礼 すぐに連行しますので
No, wait a moment.
いや　少し待て
– What?
–　え？
You said... “a sea train”?
海列車…　と言ったな？
It's a ship that puffs smoke along a sea railway from one island to another.
島から島へ 煙を上げて海の線路を走る船
Carrying passengers, goods, and other ships without being fazed by the weather,
客も物資も船も運び 天候に左右されることなく
everyone will be able to freely cross the ocean.
誰でも自由に海を渡れるようになる
Sounds too good to be true.
何を夢みてえなことを
A railway? It'd be destroyed by the first Aqua Laguna!
線路なんてそんなもの アクア･ラグナが来りゃ壊れて終わりだ
That's right! And let's not forget the sea kings!
そうだそうだ！ それに海には海王類もいるんだぞ！
Seaborne tracks wouldn't need to be fixed.
海の線路は固定する必要はない
It'll sway a little just below the surface of the water, never resisting the surf.
水面の少し下をゆらゆら揺れて 波には決して逆らわず
As if pulling in a rope, the sea train will use the tracks as a guide.
海列車はロープを手繰るように その線路を道しるべとするだけだ
On top of that, I'll add a mechanism
さらに線路とパドルの間に
between the paddles and the tracks that creates a discordant sound to drive away fish.
魚たちの嫌がる不協和音を出す 仕組みを考えている
Such a device would keep the sea kings from nearing the railway.
そうすれば 海王類も線路に近づかなくなる
Would something like that work?
できるのか？そんなこと
By uniting Saint Poplar, Pucci, San Faldo, and this island,
セント･ポプ　ラプッチ　サン･ファルド この島を結べば
we can grow our industries through mutual trade.
それぞれの交易で産業は発展できる
Incredible...!
すてき
I should finish the blueprints soon, but it's not a job for just any shipwright.
じきに設計図が完成するが そこらの船大工に造れるほど単純じゃねえ
What about a stop at Enies Lobby?
そこにエニエス･ロビーをつなぐことは？
No problem!
もちろん可能だ
Once this technology is completed and it spreads across the seas,
この技術が完成し やがて海を越えれば
it would damn well change relations among the world's islands.
世界中の島々の交渉がドンと変わる
The sea train is the hope of Water Seven!
海列車はウォーターセブンの希望だ！
How long will it take?
何年かかる？
Ten years.
10年
Then build it!
では造ってみせよ
Tom the Shipwright,
造船技師トムに
I hereby give you a ten-year reprieve to develop the sea train!
海列車の開発期間として 10年の執行猶予を言い渡す
This is incredible!
すげえぞ！
Let's go, Tom!
頑張れ　トム！
Save Water Seven!
ウォーターセブンを救ってくれ！
I'm damn still alive!
ドンと生きてた！
This is no laughing matter, Mr. Tom!
笑いごっちゃないよトムさん
A chill ran down my spine at the thought of what was to come.
来る時が来たと思って 背筋が凍ったよあたしゃ
But now, if everything goes well, they might drop case concerning Roger.
まあしかし　これでうまくいけば ロジャーの件は忘れてもらえそうだね
Well...! I gotta say, you're amazing, Mr. Tom!
ンマー！だけど トムさん やっぱすげえよな
You had this great idea right up your sleeve and blew everyone away!
あんなこと考えてたなんて！ みんな圧倒されてたもんな
The sea train's really–
やっぱ海列…
Thanks for the food!
ごちそうさん！
Yokozuna, you're learning the front crawl.
来いヨコヅナ クロール教えてやる
Hey, what the hell, Franky?! You've been sulking for awhile now!
おいフランキー！何だよ！ お前さっきから膨れてよ
Shut up! All this crap is pissing me off!
うるっせえな！ 俺は怒ってんだ何もかもに！
Gold Roger's ship is the only one in the world to circumnavigate the Grand Line!
ゴールド･ロジャーの船は グランドラインを１周した世界で１隻の船だぞ
Why does Mr. Tom need to be executed for making such an amazing ship?!
そんなすげえ船を造ったトムさんが 何で死刑にされなきゃいけねえんだ！
The onlookers were acting like it's only natural,
周りのヤツらも それが当たり前みたいに言いやがって！
but those idiots can't even build a raft!
イカダ１隻も作れねえバカたちが！
I know what's going on!
俺は知ってんだ！
Our company is under a bridge because the town drove you out over Roger's ship, right?!
こんな橋の下に会社があるのもロジャーの船のことで 町のヤツらから追い出されたからだろ！
Why does the world's best shipwright have to deal with this crap?!
世界一の船大工が 何でこんな目に遭わなきゃならねえんだよ！
What's so funny, you horned tanuki?!
何がおかしいんだこの角ダヌキ！
Get off him, Flunky! I won't stand for it!
誰に当たってんだバカンキー！ 許さねえぞ！
And I won't stand for him dying!
本人がこうなのも許せねえんだ
No, no! That's all wrong!
違う違う！そうじゃない！
Push the water as far back as you can!
思いっきり水をかいて 後ろに押し出すんだ
No, that's not it! You have to stroke harder!
ダメだ！ダメだ！ もっとこうガバーッとかくんだよ！
What the hell is with him?
ったく何なんだよ
You should just kick that idiot out!
あんなアホ追い出しちまえばいいんだ
Well, don't say that. He's a shipwright like you and me.
まあ　そう言うな 一緒に船を造る仲間なんだ
His skills are already near the level of the other craftsmen on the island.
造船技術も既に 島の職人たちと比べても大差ねえし
His creations are a bit dangerous though.
造るものは危なっかしいがな
He's always been a straight shooter.
あいつはいつでもまっすぐなだけよ
This kid damn well showed up on Scrap Island two years ago,
２年前にドンと廃船島に現れたガキが
and to my surprise had made a cannon out of junk.
ガラクタを使って 大砲を造っていたのには驚いた
Hey, man, take me in! My parents ditched me!
おっさん　俺拾ってくれ！ 親から見捨てられたんだ！
He said his parents threw him off their ship because they couldn't handle him.
聞けば“手に負えねえガキだ”と 親に船から放り出されたんだという
Seems like they were pirates, but lousy ones, y'know?
どこぞのろくでもねえ海賊のようだが
It's hilarious!
傑作！
Mr. Tom...
トムさん
He's tough, don't you think?
たくましいじゃないの
Despite his background, he turned out all right.
それでもあいつは曲がってねえんだ
You two will surely be world-class shipwrights someday.
おめえら２人はいつか必ず 世界に通用する造船技師になるんだ
Get along with one another.
仲よくやんな
That's impossible for Franky. Every fiber of him is crazy.
フランキーには無理だね 細胞からイカれてんだあいつは
Anyway, once I finish the blueprints, we'll start building the sea train!
さあ　設計図ができしだい 海列車を造り出すぞ
Sure. But there's no way he'll help us.
おう… だけどあいつきっと手伝わねえよ
He's welcome to do as he likes!
好きにしたらいいとも
Suicide?
自殺？
I heard it was the president of the dock four shipbuilding company.
４番の造船会社の社長だと
Must've been the accident...
あの事故のせいだ
He took his own ship out to buy lumber since they were running low,
物資がねえから 自らの船で木材を買いに出て
but he got fifty people killed at sea.
海で50人死なせたって
His shipyard is closing down too.
造船所も閉鎖だそうだ
People are so fragile...
弱えな　人間なんて
Is this island about done for?
もうダメなのか　この島は…
Hey!
おーい！
Did you guys hear about Scrap Island?
お前ら聞いたか？廃船島の話
H-Hey, is that true?!
お…　おい！それ本当かよ？
You're telling me Tom's Workers finished the sea train?!
トムズワーカーズが 海列車を完成させただと！？
Wow! Will this ship really run?!
うわっ！本当に走んのか？こんな船が！
It's gotta be dangerous. A criminal made it.
危ねえよ 犯罪者の造った船なんて
I want to ride.
私乗る
Then... I guess I will too.
あ…　じゃあ俺も
Tom, will you give us the rundown?!
トム！説明はなしか？
We're leaving. All aboard!
出航するよ　乗っとくれ
It's moving!
動いた！
The paddles are grabbing the railway!
パドルが線路をつかんでる！
Wow! Look at it go!
すごい　走ってる！
Twelve years ago...
今より12年前の話
leaving an isolated, dying city with anxious people on board...
この時初めて閉ざされ　廃れゆく町から 悩まされる人々を乗せて…
the sea train Puffing Tom crossed the sea for the first time.
海列車パッフィングトムは海を渡った
I see...
なるほど
So this dingy warehouse was once the Tom's Workers shipbuilding company's main office, huh?
この薄汚い倉庫は かつての造船会社トムズワーカーズの本社か
A shipbuilding company?
造船会社？
Tom, Iceburg, and Cutty Flam...
トム　アイスバーグ　カティ･フラム
This place must hold memories of the three of you building ships, correct?
３人で造船にいそしんだ 思い出の場所というわけだな
Calling it a “secret hideout” is rather endearing.
それを秘密基地と呼ぶとは ずいぶんかわいげのあることをするもんだな
Shut your hole!
黙れ！
Get the hell outta here already!
さっさとここから出ろ！
We'll go once we get what we came for... shipwright Cutty Flam.
もらうべきものをもらってからだ 船大工カティ･フラム
There aren't any blueprints here!
設計図はここにはねえよ！
Well, that's the answer I'd expect.
まっ　当然といえば当然の答え
Hey!
おい！
Kalifa!
カリファ！
Ow...!
痛え…
Wh-Wh-Wh-What do I do?!
どど…　どうしよう俺
You son of a bitch...!
てめえ…
We've got plenty of time to get the truth out of you.
別に 今すぐ答える必要もないさ
We have a trump card.
我々には切り札がある
It may have happened eight years ago,
８年も昔の話だが
but it seems you're also guilty of some crimes...
君は犯罪を犯してるらしいな
just like Tom.
トムと同じように
Screw you! Mr. Tom was no criminal!
ふざけるな！ トムさんは犯罪者じゃねえ！
Don't talk to me like you know anything about it,
てめえなんかが分かったふうな口利くな！
you little punk!
ガキが！
Mr. Tom...!
トムさん…
Stay right there!
来ないで！
Calm down.
騒ぐな
As a criminal, you should know the consequences of your actions.
犯罪者ならば 自分がどういう道をたどるか分かるはずだ
Franky...
フランキー
don't interfere with what I'm about to do...
これから起こることに口を出すな
no matter what!
絶対に！
You punks know nothing...
てめえらがどれほど
about Mr. Tom...
トムさんを
or about Water Seven!
このウォーターセブンを知ってるってんだよ！
So the judicial ship will be here in three days?
３日後に司法船が来るんですって？
Ah, Tom's trial, right?
いよいよトムの裁判か
I wonder how it'll turn out.
どうなるのかしら？
He should be fine.
大丈夫だろう
Surely.
そうね
After all, he fulfilled his promise.
ちゃんと約束を果たしたんですもんね
Indubitably.
ああ
Carry this load to the dock.
届いた木材をドックへ運び込め
How'd the negotiations with Saint Poplar go?
セント･ポプラでの交渉はうまくいったか？
Not good.
まだダメだ
They're looking to take advantage of our lack of resources.
あいつら資材のねえ俺たちの足元を見やがる
Same with the steel from San Faldo.
サン･ファルドの鉄もそうだ
These prices will cause shipyards to go into the red!
あんなに高くちゃ結局造船所は赤字だぜ
But we'll work it out next time for sure!
でも次こそ何とかしてやろうじゃねえか！
– Yeah! That's right!
–　おおー！そうだそうだ！
Everyone's happy to travel to the other islands...
海を渡れることにみんな喜んでるけど
but trading with them seems to be tricky.
他の島との交易は難航らしい
The sea train hasn't changed the city much...
これでも町は変わらねえのかな
At least the people are buzzing.
だが人間に活気がある
Results don't happen overnight, Iceburg.
結果はすぐについてこねえよアイスバーグ
Once a man's done all he can, he should keep his head held damn high!
やれるだけのことをやったら 男はドンと胸を張ってりゃいいんだ
Alright.
ああ
Hello and good day, sir.
どうもこんにちは
Would you happen to be the master shipwright Mr. Tom?
あなたですか？ 造船技師のミスター･トムとは
Oh, how I've looked for you!
いやあ　捜しました
Hm?
ん？
Pardon me, but I have a matter to–
すみませんが 少々お話…
Uh...
あの…
Don't interrupt me! Stand down!
口を挟むな　下がってろ！
– Yes, sir!
–　はっ
I have a matter to dis–
少々お話をさせていただき…
I-I am...
わっ　私は…
Cipher Pol Number 5's...
サイファーポールナンバー５の
Spandam!
スパンダ…
– Agent Spandam!
–　スパンダムさん！ スパンダムさん！
Oh! Sorry 'bout that!
おう！悪い
I don't know who you are, but it looks like my cannon salute hit you.
誰だか知らねえが 祝砲が当たっちまった
That aside...
そして
I feel super! Battle Franky 35 is back!
スーパー！ バトルフランキー35号　帰還！
I killed a sea king!
海王類をしとめたぜ！
Look at how big it is! This monster's gotta be at least 100 meters long!
見よ！このでかさ 全長100メートルはあろうかって怪物だ！
That idiot... He never learns.
あのバカは… また性懲りもなく
Ahh, you asshole! Stop it, Jerkburg!
だーっ！ てめえ！やめろ！このアホバーグ！
When will you listen?!
何度言わせるんだ！
You keep building all these damn battleships!
次から次へといまだに こんな戦艦造り続けやがって
Enough is enough already!
いいかげんにしろよ！
If you can't do it yourself, then today's the day I dismantle them for you!
お前にできねえなら 今日という今日は俺が全部処分してやる！
Screw you!
ふざけるな！
They're my precious battleships!
俺の大事な戦艦だぞ
No way I'd let you do something like that!
そんな勝手なことさせるか！
Well...! Listen, Franky!
ンマーいいか？フランキー
You killed a sea king, right?
お前海王類をしとめたんだろ？
That means this is a deadly weapon.
これはそれほどの凶器だってことだ
I don't understand how you can leave dozens of these things lying around.
そんなもんを何十隻も放置できる お前の神経が分からねえ！
It's not like I intend to attack people with them!
別に人を攻撃するわけじゃねえだろうが！
It's not about your intentions!
お前の意志どうこうじゃねえ
You're culpable for creating such weapons, Flunky!
凶器を存在させた責任を 問いかけてんだ　バカンキー！
W-Wait...
ちょっ　ちょ…
Mr. Tom, say something!
トムさん！何とか言ってくれよ！
Flunky is a disgrace to our company!
我が社の面汚しだバカンキーは！
Again with calling him "Flunky"!
またバカンキーって
W-Wait just a minute, please!
ちょっと！お待ちくださいよ！
First, I would like an apology. Then, I would like you to hear me out!
まずはちゃんと謝ってほしい そして私の話を聞いてほしい！
You're with the government?
政府の人間だな？
Is this about my trial?
裁判の件か？
Huh? What're you talking about?
え？何です？それは
No, sir, I don't know anything about that.
いえ　そちらのほうは 存じていませんが
Hm?
ん？
Where's Mr. Tom?
トムさんはどうした？
They wanted to talk alone.
２人きりで話すんだと
He's in the brick warehouse with some government guy.
レンガ倉庫にいるよ　政府のヤツと
Span... What was it again?
スパン…　何だっけ？
Spanda... something or other.
スパンダ何とかだ
Sounds like he's not affiliated with the judicial ship.
ありゃあ司法船とは別の役人だね
They're not very well organized.
まとまりのねえヤツらだよ
I don't know! I don't have any blueprints like that!
知らん！ そんなものの設計図は持ってねえ
Nonsense!
ウソをつけ！
Don't trample my humility by playing innocent!
人が下手に出てりゃシラを切り倒しやがって
We've already combed through Water Seven's past!
ウォーターセブンをさかのぼり もう調べはついてるんだ！
If we search the premises, we'll find them in no time!
身の回りを取り調べれば あっという間に現物が出てくる
Do you even have the authority to investigate me?
わしを調べる権限がお前らにあるのか？
You bet your ass we do, Tom!
あるともトム
I already know you're the master criminal who built Gold Roger's ship!
お前がゴールド･ロジャーの船を造った 大罪人だってのも　何と調査済みだ
And since you're a criminal, your rights are as good as forfeit.
罪人である以上 お前の身柄はこちらの自由になるわけだ
Oh, the government already knows all about that.
そんなことは　とうに政府に漏れてる
What?!
何！？
That's absurd!
そんなバカな
Then why are you working as a shipwright instead of being locked away in a cell?
じゃあ　なぜ貴様は捕まらず ここで船大工をやってるんだ！
Do as an intelligence agent does and figure it out. So long!
諜報部員なら自分で調べろ じゃあな
Hey, wait! I was still talking with you!
おい待て！話はまだだ！
Do you know who I am?!
俺を誰だと思ってるんだ！
Oh, that?
何だ　そのことかい
Tom followed through on the promise he made on the judicial ship.
トムなら司法船との約束を果たしたからな
The charges should be dropped when he's tried in three days.
３日後の裁判で罪は帳消しになるだろう
Tom's a great man.
偉大な男だよ　トムは
You've gotta be kidding...
冗談じゃねえ
They'll drop a serious charge related to Roger?
ロジャーに関わる大罪が帳消しだと？
So something like that really does exist.
やはりそんなものが存在したか
Yes, sir.
はい
Naturally, pirates are looking for the blueprints as well.
当然この設計図を嗅ぎ回る海賊もいます
In the unlikely event they were to fall into nongovernmental hands,
万が一 政府以外の誰かの手にそれが渡った場合
the government would no longer have a fighting chance.
もはや 政府に太刀打ちするすべはありません
It has been ten years since the dawn of the so-called Great Pirate Era.
世に言う大海賊時代幕開けから10年以上経過し
Pirates have quickly gained power and grown more numerous.
海賊どもはみるみる力をつけ 数も増加するばかり
We cannot stand idly by while the ancient weapons are revived!
古代兵器の復活阻止など のんびりとしたことを言ってる場合ではありません
We, who uphold justice, should possess that firepower!
正義を掲げる我々こそこれくらいの牙を持たねば！
With the ancient weapon in our hands, we can end this Great Pirate Era!
古代兵器は我々が所持し この大海賊時代を撃ち払うのです！
Times are changing. You may have a point with what you said.
時代は動いている 一理なくもないが…
First get us those blueprints, then we'll talk more.
ならばその設計図とやらをまず手に入れてみせろ 話はその先だ
We're leaving this matter to you, Spandam.
この件お前に一任しようスパンダム
Leave it me! You won't regret it.
はっ！お任せください
After all my investigating, my chance has finally come!
さんざん苦労を積み重ね 調べ上げて得たこのチャンスを
I'm not just gonna watch it go up in smoke!
みすみす棒に振ってたまるか！
Let's go!
行くぞ！
Dammit! I'm up a creek if he's exonerated!
クソッ　ヤツが犯罪者でなくちゃ 困るんだよ　俺が！
– Agent Spandam!
–　スパンダムさん！
Forget exoneration...
何が帳消し…
Just you watch, you smug bastard.
見てやがれ　生意気な
Hey! Call in five more intelligence agents!
おい！ あと５人諜報部員を呼びつけろ
– Yes, sir!
–　はっ！
Agent Spandam!
–　スパンダムさん！
Iceburg. Franky.
アイスバーグ　フランキー
Huh?
ん？
Come here for a second.
２人ともこっちへ来い
I need to entrust something important to you.
大切なものをお前たちに預けたい
Wh-Why would someone design this?!
な…　何のためにこんなものが…
C-C-Can humans build something like this?!
こ…　こんなもん人間に造れんのか？
It's the worst monstrosity in the history of shipbuilding.
造船史上最悪の　化け物だ
The government was tipped off about these blueprints and is moving in.
政府がこの設計図の存在に気づいて 動きだしている
It's too dangerous for me to keep them.
わしが持っていてはもう危ねえ
I'm scared, but... I understand. We'll take them.
怖えけど… 分かった　受け取るよ
So freaking cool...! Hey, Iceburg, we should build it!
すんげえ！アイスバーグ おい！これ造ってみようぜ！
You idiot!
バカ野郎！
That hurt!
いってえ…
Think before you speak!
少しは考えて物言え！
I'll take care of these.
これは俺が管理する
If we let something like this come into being...
こんなもん この世に存在さしちまったら…
Huh?
ん？
Yeah, the world would be doomed.
ああ　世界は滅ぶ
Anyway, it's up to you two what you do with those.
しかしもう どうしようとおめえらの自由さ
If push comes to shove, destroy 'em.
ヤバくなったら捨てたっていい
Mr. Tom...
トムさん
While we're here...
ついでに１つ
I need to share one other cause for concern.
わしの不安要素も伝えておく